bankinnovation.net 2019-10-24

# Online Legal, Privacy and Information Usage Terms | Royal Media

[Updated as of December 6, 2018]

Royal Media provides market knowledge in several industry sectors through its publications, conferences and custom media products. These online legal, privacy and information usage terms (collectively, “Terms of Use”) reflect our commitment to serve you and explains how we intend to protect your privacy. These Terms of Use cover Royal Media’s treatment of information we collect when you are on our site and when you use our services. These Terms of Use also cover our treatment of any personally identifiable information our business partners share with us. These Terms of Use do not apply to the practices of companies Royal Media does not own or control, including operators of sites to which you may link from the Royal Media website. Royal Media has created these Terms of Use to demonstrate our firm commitment to protect your privacy and to fully disclose what information we collect and how we use it.

**_Lawful Basis for Collection and Processing of Information_** :

We take your privacy seriously and will only use personal data to provide the products and services you have requested from us. We only collect and process personal information where we have a lawful basis for doing so, such as the following:

**User consent –  **This is where you have given us explicit permission to obtain and process personal information for a given purpose.

**Legitimate business purposes –  **This is where we have a legitimate interest, as a business, to process personal information, such where the user is a client of Royal Media or for the purpose of fraud prevention or ensuring network security. We take due care to balance our interests against your right to privacy.

**Contractual necessity –  **This is where we have to process personal information to meet our contractual obligations. For example, if you are a print subscriber, we would need to process your delivery address to fulfill your subscription.

**Legal obligation –  **This is where we have to process personal information in order to comply with applicable law.

**_Withdrawal of Consent to Use or Processing of Information:_**

To the extent that the legal basis for Royal Media’s use or processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time by contacting us, as provided below. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of information processing before the withdrawal. You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from us by using the unsubscribe link within each email, updating your email preferences within your account settings menu, or by contacting us as provided below to have your contact information removed from our promotional email list or registration database.

**_COOKIES POLICY_**

**_Use of Cookies; Tracking Activity on Our Website_**

We have developed this Cookies Policy in order to explain how we use cookies and similar technologies (referred to together as “cookies”) on this website and to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of your personal information.

Cookies are small text files containing user IDs that are automatically placed on your computer or other device by when you visit a website. The cookies are stored by the internet browser. The browser sends the cookies back to the website on each subsequent visit, allowing the website to recognize your computer or device. This recognition enables the website provider to observe your activity on the website, deliver a personalized, responsive service and improve the website.

The first time that you visit our website, we notify you about our use of cookies through a notification banner. By continuing to use the website, you consent to our use of cookies as described in this Cookies Policy. However, you can choose whether or not to continue accepting cookies at any later time. Information on how to manage cookies is set out later in this Cookies Policy.

When you browse royalmedia.com and have not registered for any online service from Royal Media, personally identifiable information—such as your name, address, phone number, and e-mail address—is not collected.

However, we track how our site is used by both visitors and our registered customers. One way we track is by using cookies. Cookies collect information that includes the server your computer is logged onto, your browser type, and whether you responded to a Royal Media banner ad from outside our site or through an e-mail link. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive, pass on computer viruses, or capture your e-mail address or any other personally identifiable information.

Using cookies enables us to recognize your computer if you or someone else using your computer returns to our site, and to keep track of the pages on our site that you or another user of your computer visit, and whether or not you or another user of your computer respond to certain banner ads or special offers. We use this information to help us present more relevant offers and information.

You can adjust your computer browser settings so that you are informed when a cookie is being placed on your browser. You can also set your browser to decline or accept all cookies. However, if you choose to register for an online service on royalmedia.com, you must accept cookies in order to access Royal Media site pages that enable you to view your confidential account information. These cookies are essential for site administration and security.

**_Categories of Cookies_**

Cookies can be “Session Cookies” or “Persistent Cookies”. Session Cookies allow a website to link a series of your actions during one browser session. Session Cookies expire after a browser session and are therefore not stored on your computer or device afterward. Persistent Cookies are stored on your computer or device between browser sessions and can be used when you make subsequent visits to the website – for example, to remember your website preferences, such as font size.

**_Cookies We Use and their Purpose_**

To support our services, we or our service providers may use one or more of the following cookies for the purposes set forth below:

**_Essential Cookies:_** These cookies are essential to provide you with services available through our website and to enable you to use some of its features. Without these cookies, the services that you have asked for cannot be provided, and we only use these cookies to provide you with those services.

**_Functionality Cookies_** : These cookies allow us to remember choices you make when you use our services. The purpose of these cookies is to provide you with a more personal experience and to avoid you having to re-enter your preferences every time you visit our website.

**_Analytics and Performance Cookies_ :** These cookies are used to collect information about traffic to our website and how users use our website and services. The information gathered does not identify any individual visitor. The information is aggregated and therefore anonymous. It includes the number of visitors to our website, the websites that referred them to our website, the pages that they visited on our Website, what time of day they visited our website, whether they have visited our website before, and other similar information. We use this information to help operate our website more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information and to monitor the level of activity on our website. We use Google Analytics for this purpose. Google Analytics uses its own cookies. It is only used to improve how our website works. You can find out more information about Google Analytics cookies here:  <https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies>. You can find out more about how Google protects your data here: <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>.

**_Managing Cookies_**

You always have a choice over whether or not to accept cookies. When you first visit our website and we notify you about our use of cookies, you can choose not to consent to such use. If you consent and continue to use the website, you are consenting to our use of cookies for the time being. However, you can choose not to continue accepting cookies at any later time. In this section, we describe ways to manage cookies, including how to disable them.

You can manage cookies through the settings of your internet browser. You can choose to block or restrict cookies from being placed on your computer or device. You can also review periodically review the cookies that have been placed there and disable some or all of them.

Please be aware that if you choose not to accept certain cookies, it may mean we are unable to provide you with some services or features of our website.

**_Further Information Regarding Cookies_** : You can find more information about cookies and how they work, what cookies have been set on your computer or mobile device and how to manage and delete them at [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

_______

**PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ON OUR WEBSITE**

Whether or not you are a registered user on our website, if you purchase or apply for Royal Media products or services on royalmedia.com, we may request that you provide your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, and other personal information in order to provide the product or service to you or to process your application for the product or service. And, if you receive an e-mail offer from Royal Media, we may record whether you “click through” to view or respond to the offer.

**_How We Use Personal Information_**

We use information collected on our site to process transactions you conduct on our website, and to process requests and deliver the products and services you enroll in or apply for. To do this, it may be necessary to share this information with carefully selected vendors and business partners we work with. We also may use it, together with information we have about you as a Royal Media customer, publicly available information, and preferences you indicate, to customize your online experience and to provide you with more relevant offers and updates.

**_How We Use Your E-mail Address_**

Should you provide it to us, we may use your e-mail address to send you the following types of e-mail messages:

  * Occasional updates about our products and services, as well as Royal Media marketing offers.
  * Regularly scheduled e-mail newsletters related to the Royal Media products or services you are enrolled in.
  * Valuable offers from our business partners that we send you on their behalf.
  * Service notifications related to your account(s).
  * Optional Royal Media e-mail newsletters. We occasionally invite customers to sign up for these newsletters via e-mail or other communications, and we also post sign up forms on the Royal Media site.
  * When we send e-mail to you, we may be able to identify information about your e-mail address, such as whether you can view graphic-rich HTML e-mail. If your e-mail address is HTML-enabled, we may choose to send you graphic-rich HTML e-mail messages.

**_Ads That Link to Our Website_**

Royal Media hires other companies to place our banner ads on other websites and to perform tracking and reporting activities (“third-party advertisement servers”). They do not collect personally identifiable information in doing this work for us, and we do not give any personally identifiable information to them.

Third-party advertisement servers are subject to their own privacy policies. If you would like more information about the privacy policies of these third-party advertisement servers, including information on how to opt out of their tracking methods, we refer you to the privacy policies of their websites.

**_Royal Media Events_**

Royal Media events are produced for a variety of sponsors. All data collected during the registration of such events may be shared with those sponsors. This data is governed by the individual sponsor’s privacy policy and may be used by the sponsor for follow-up purposes. Please be aware you are directly providing your personally identifiable information to that advertiser. Please visit the sponsor’s web site to review its privacy policy. Should you register for a Royal Media-sponsored conference or other event, you are consenting to provide your personally identifiable information to that sponsor. For details on how event sponsors use the information you provide, please contact the sponsor directly.

**_Applicability of Privacy Policy to Children_**. We do not knowingly solicit data online from or market online to children under the age of 18.

**_Compliance with Enforcement Requests and Applicable Laws; Enforcement of Our Rights_** : In exceptional circumstances, we may share information about you with a third-party if we believe that sharing is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with any applicable laws, legal process or governmental request, (b) enforce our agreements, policies and terms of service, (c) protect the security or integrity of our products and services, (d) protect Royal Media, our customers or the public from harm or illegal activities, or (e) respond to an emergency which we believe in good faith requires us to disclose information to assist in preventing the death or serious bodily injury of any person.

**_Business Transfers_** : We may share or transfer information we collect under this privacy policy in connection with any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company. You will be notified via email and/or a general notice on our Website if a transaction takes place, as well as any choices you may have regarding your information.

**_Verification, Updating, Correction or Deletion of Information_**

You may check your information to verify, update or correct it, and to have any of your information deleted. If you created an account on our website, you can access and change your online profile. You can also ask to review any information we have retained, how we have used it, and to whom we have disclosed it by contacting us below under the heading “Contacting Royal Media”. Subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law, and provided we can authenticate your identity, you will be given reasonable access to your personal information and will be entitled to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate. You may also ask us to change your preferences regarding how we use or disclose your information or let us know that you do not wish to receive any further communication from us.

Upon request, we will provide you with your personal information in a machine-readable format.

We may refuse to comply with a request if the request is manifestly unfounded or excessive or repetitive in nature.  We may be entitled to refuse requests, wholly or partly, where exceptions under applicable law apply. We may refuse a request for erasure of personal information, for example, where the processing is necessary to comply with a legal obligation or necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims or for record-keeping purposes.

**Retention of Information:**

Royal Media will retain and use your personally identifiable information for as long as needed to provide you with its services, as necessary to comply with our obligations under these Terms of Use and at law, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements and for backup purposes. When it is no longer required, we will delete your personal information. Additionally, in certain circumstances, registered users in the European Union may also have the right of portability of their personally identifiable information.

**_Compliance with Law_ :**

We will only process your personal information in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws, including the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).  For the purposes of EU data protection legislation, the data controller is Royal News Corp., 8 West 38th Street, Suite 901, New York, NY 10018-6229, telephone (212) 564-8972, email [info@royalmedia.com](mailto:info@royalmedia.com).

**We do not collect or process the following categories of data unless required by law:**

  * Race or ethnic origin
  * Political opinions
  * Religious or philosophical beliefs
  * Trade union memberships
  * Genetic or biometric data
  * Health or mortality data
  * Sex life or sexual orientation

**Information from users outside the United States and consent to transfer information:**  

Our website is operated in the United States.  If you are located in another jurisdiction, please be aware that information you provide to us will be transferred to, stored and processed in the United States.  By using our services or website or providing us with any information, you consent to this transfer, processing, and storage of your information in the United States, a jurisdiction in which the privacy laws may not be as comprehensive as those in the country where you reside or are a citizen. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with these Terms of Use. However, no system is completely secure or error-free. We do not, and cannot, guarantee the complete security of your information.

**California Privacy Rights Requirements.   **We do not share personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, as defined by California Civil Code Section 1798.83, unless we give you choice (opt-in or opt-out) before sharing with those third parties.  If you are a California resident and you have questions about our practices with respect to sharing information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes and your ability to exercise choice, please contact us by sending an email to [info@royalmedia.com](mailto:info@royalmedia.com). You must put the statement “My California Privacy Rights” in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. Please note that we will not accept inquiries via the telephone or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.

**California Privacy Rights Requirements.   ** If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your personal information by us to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes and to opt-out of the disclosure of personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. You may contact us for such information or to opt out of the sharing of your personal information with third parties for marketing purposes at any time by contacting us as described below in “Contacting Royal Media”. You must put the statement “My California Privacy Rights” in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In the body of your request, please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. Please note that we will not accept inquiries via the telephone or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.

**Do Not Track** : Some browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” (DNT) features that can send a signal to the websites you visit indicating that you do not wish to be tracked. Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the DNT signal, our website does not currently respond to DNT signals. You can use the range of other tools we provide to control data collection and use, as described above. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

**COPYRIGHTS, TRADEMARKS AND OTHER INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY**.

All material contained on our website and the compilation of it, are our property and are protected by United States and international copyright laws. All trademarks, service marks and trade names also are proprietary to us. No material from our websites may be copied, reproduced, republished, uploaded, posted, transmitted or distributed in any way without the consent of Royal Media. Except as may be permitted by law, you must obtain our written permission before using any copyrighted material on our website. You do not acquire any ownership rights by downloading material from our website. Royal Media retains all rights and privileges to the content and marks on royalmedia.com. 2018 © Royal Media

**MODIFICATIONS OF TERMS**.

We may modify these Terms of Use at any time and at our sole discretion by posting the modified Terms of Use on our website. The modifications will be effective upon posting (unless some other date is specified). You should review these Terms of Use periodically so that you are aware of any modifications. Your use of our website constitutes your acceptance of the Terms of Use in their then-current form.

**CONTACTING ROYAL MEDIA/QUESTIONS OR COMMENTS**.

Feel free to address any questions or comments regarding our Terms of Use, including our Privacy Policy and Cookies Policy, to:

**Royal Media Group**  
8 West 38th Street, Suite 901  
New York, NY 10018-6229  
Phone: 212 564 8972  
Email: info@royalmedia.com
